Guide to the Collection of Student and Alumni Surveys of Service in World War I MC 92
New York University Archives
Collection of Student and Alumni Surveys of Service in World War I
1920-1924
1922-1924
New York University Archives
Mindil, Clinton
MC 92
0.5 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
The Student and Alumni Surveys of Service in World War I Collection contains all of the materials compiled by Professor Clinton Mindil to create a comprehensive list of the individuals affiliated with New York University who served in the war. These materials include a list containing the name, rank, service dates, and special honors of the faculty, students, and alumni of NYU who served in the first World War, as well as the questionnaires distributed by Mindil to collect the information. Though the materials were never published, the information was originally collected with the intention of creating an official New York University World War Memorial Volume.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Historical Note
Following the end of World War I, an effort was made to create a War Record documenting the names and short biographical narratives of all the students, alumni, and faculty of New York University who served in the war. Between the spring of 1920 and summer of 1922 Clinton Mindil, a professor of English at NYU, distributed questionnaires to individuals affiliated with the university who were known or believed to have served in the war. The questionnaire was circulated six times with the intention of compiling a comprehensive list of names to publish a New York University World War Memorial Volume through the New York University Press. Not all of the distributed questionnaires were completed and returned, and the volume was never published, however, the list of names and completed questionnaires provide a deeper look at how NYU was involved in and affected by the war.
Related Materials
The Clinton Mindil Collection on NYU Alumni in World War I (MC 68)
Scope and Contents
The materials in the World War I Collection were compiled between the spring of 1920 and the summer of 1922 with the intention of publishing a New York University World War Memorial Volume. The collection contains an alphabetical list of NYU faculty, students, and alumni who served in the war as well as the completed questionnaires that were circulated in order to compile the information. The list provides the name, rank, service dates, and special honors of the individuals who served in the war and replied to the questionnaire. Since not all of the questionnaires were replied to the list is not exhaustive, however, it is extensive and includes the records of the individuals associated with New York University who died in the war.
World War, 1914-1918.; Universities and Colleges -- Alumni and alumnae.
- Compiler's Note, Letter, Abbreviations, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alumni and Students: A-C, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alumni and Students: D-G, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alumni and Students: H-K, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alumni and Students: L-O, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Alumni and Students: P-S, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alumni and Students: T-Z, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alumni and Students who Died During War, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Student Army Training Corps, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Questionnaires, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Questionnaires--Died During War, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)